so now that we have seen how to or more
bit histories work let's do a quiz about
them let's say we have an n-bit history
with a two bit counter per history in
each predictor entry let's say that we
need a thousand twenty four entries in
order for each branch to and each other
instruction to have its own entry so
that they don't interfere with each
other so for the length of the history
of one four eight and 16 what is the
cost of the entire predictor in bits I'm
going to tell you that the cost with a
1-bit history is the one bit of history
and two two bit counters per entries
it's going to be five bits times 1,024
is this predictor good for each of the
predictors for a pattern of N and NT
that repeats and we know already that
the one bit history predictor is not
good for this pattern because it's too
long for it and finally what is the
number of two bit counters in an entry
that we actually use when trying to
predict the repeating NT pattern meaning
not taken taken not taken taken and so
on we already know that in the N equals
1 predictor we need to use both of our
counters so the answer is to to further
help you I'm going to tell you that the
cost of an N equals 4 predictor should
be the history is 4 plus 2 bit predictor
x' I need 2 to the 4th of them times a
thousand 24 you can compute what this is
you should put a real number here so you
should multiply things out for these two
here you should just say yes or no yes
if the predictor will predict this
successfully after the initial warmup
period no if it won't and then how many
two bit counters are we using for the
not taken taken not taken taken pattern
in this particular predictor